DEEPIKA D

Data Analyst

Mob: +91 9791184347 ⊠: ddeepika1206@gmail.com

SUMMARY

An analytical software engineer with six years of experience in Information Technology and has the ability to identify business needs and develop solutions that drive process efficiency and accuracy. Seeking a career opportunity to bring detail and precision into data analysis. Experience with SDLC and Agile methodologies. Good communication and leadership skills.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

1. Agility Logistics (GIL Shared Services)

(Mar 2021 - Present)

PROJECT NAME : Decision support system Power BI

JOB ROLE : Senior Process Associate

> Description:

Preparing dashboards that includes shipment details, Robotic Process Automation, Balance Score card, Overbilled invoices and financial summary.

> Responsibilities:

- Developed freight forwarding dashboards using DAX queries to create calculated columns and measures
- Used power query and power pivot for data analysis
- Have used DAX studio to analyse the performance and Tabular editor in Power BI
- Enablement of Power Automate in all dashboards.
- Logged the work in JIRA to track the project stage and development.
- Published Power BI Reports in the required originations and Made Power BI Dashboards available in Web clients and mobile apps
- Connected to live data using Power BI dataset from Microsoft Azure
- Explore data in a variety of ways and across multiple visualizations using Power BI
- Used Power BI Gateways to keep the dashboards and reports up to date.

2. Infosys Limited

(Jun 2014-Jun 2019) Technology Analyst

During five years of experience with Infosys, I have worked in projects. Worked as environment support analyst in EMTL and Programmer analyst in Data analytics department.

PROJECT - 1 : Finance COE Analytics (from Sep 2017- Jun 2019)

JOB ROLE : Programmer analyst

> Description:

Migrated Finance CoE dashboards from Tableau and PowerBI to Qlikview.

> Responsibilities:

- Work with business analyst groups to ascertain their database reporting needs.
- Take the database reporting needs and turn them into powerful SQL queries that will extract data and compile it into meaningful reports.
- Perform data loads and routine updates on basis of requirement.
- Extracting the data from different sources, Analysing them and doing transformations and operations that is required to migrate Tableau and PowerBI dashboards to Qlikview.
- Creating dashboards in Qlikview.
- Developing the data model
- Generating the KPIs, dashboards and reports in Qlikview based on the client requirements.
- Migrating the dashboard from tableau and PowerBI to Qlikview.
- After the development, involving in Support activities such as enhancements, production issues and daily refresh of the dashboards.

PROJECT - 2 : Extract, Masking, Target and Load (EMTL support)-

(Jun 2014 to July 2017)

JOB ROLE : Environment support Analyst

> Description:

Worked as a part of production support to extract the job from the source, mask the required fields and transfer to the target.

> Responsibilities:

- Monitoring batch cycles to make sure of application availability within due time.
- Analyzing the abnormalities in Batch Schedules and taking necessary actions.
- Monitoring all the production batch jobs, resolve job failure, investigating long running jobs.
- Force complete, delete, place jobs on hold/confirm status.
- Make sure that all production jobs are completed as per SLA.

SKILLS

- Power BI Developer.
- Data query language: SQL, DAX
- ❖ Agile project management : Jira software
- Basics in Tableau.
- Python.
- MS office and HTML.
- Team leadership.
- Strong in data preparation, data modelling and visualization.
- Basics of C and JAVA.
- Worked with various industries such as Logistics, Finance and Banking.

EDUCATION

SSN College Of Engineering - Bachelor Of Engineering in Bio Medical Engineering with CGPA of 8.02 (August 2010 - June 2014)

Anna University, Chennai.

CERTIFICATE

- Udemy certification in Story telling dashboard.
- Big Data foundation course certified by MSME development Institute, Chennai.
- ➤ Harvard Mentor Management course in Time management and presentation skills.

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

- Spot Award: Gold award for exceptional performance and outstanding preparing critical process at a very short notice.
- Recognized as a good communicator for giving the best and clear explanation of the analogy by LND team during the speech in weekly sessions.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth : 12-06-1992
Sex : Female
Nationality : Indian
Marital Status : Married